sammobile.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy & Cookies Policy - SamMobile

**Effective July 20, 2018**

We at SamMobile B.V. (“SamMobile”) care deeply about how your personal data is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously.  
This Privacy & Cookies Policy (“Policy”) describes what data we collect, use and share. It also describes why we collect it in the first place.  
For (EU) data protection laws including, but not limited to the GDPR, we are a “Data Controller” for the data you provide to us.  
There may be other Data Controllers such as our advertisers, please consult their privacy policies to learn more about their privacy practices.  
By using our website(s) and/or mobile application(s) (“Services”) you consent to our Privacy & Cookies Policy and our Terms & Conditions.

## Who we are

SamMobile is operated by SamMobile B.V. (Blijenbergstraat 12N, 2406 GB Alphen aan den Rijn, The Netherlands).  
Our website address is: https://www.sammobile.com. For contact information, see below.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

As stated in our Terms & Conditions, we exclusively collect personal data from people who are at least 16 years old (or older), or people under the age of 16 in the exclusive case their parents or a legal representative has read and agreed to this Privacy & Cookies Policy and has provided permission for them to provide their personal data to us to use our services.

Submission of personal identifiable information is not required in order to browse our website and we strongly urge you NOT to disclose any of your full (real) name, birth-date, personal address(es), email address(es), social media accounts or phone numbers when interacting with our visitors in the comments sections.

Collected personal data, including why:  
– **Username** , unique identifier on our website (do not use your email)  
– **Email** , to confirm your registration and reset your password, and (if you explicitly opted-in for this) send you Promotional emails from the SamMobile Team  
– **IP address** , for spam detection and for ensuring account, network and information security  
– **Country** , for Country-specific offers and statistics  
– **Gender** , for Gender-specific offers and statistics  
– **Device** , for Device-specific offers and statistics  
– **Timezone** , for localized date and time

We **do not collect** nor want to collect full (real) names, birth-dates, personal address(es), email address(es), social media accounts or phone numbers.  
We strictly operate on a **least-information** , **need-to-know basis** to guarantee the privacy of your personal data while using our services provided.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

Our contact forms are strictly used to submit support email messages to our back-end systems or to temporarily hold the details we need in case of promotions we run.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use third-party web analytics services (such as Google Analytics) on our Services. These service providers may use cookies to help us analyze where in the world you are coming from and how you use the Services provided by us. To prevent Google Analytics from using your information for analytics, you may install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on by [clicking here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). The Google Analytics service privacy policy is available here: https://policies.google.com/privacy

### Advertisements

We use both our own advertisements to promote our own services, deals or promotions, as well as third-party web advertisement services (such as Google AdSense). The Google Adsense service privacy policy is available here: https://policies.google.com/privacy

### Performance, Security and Geo-location

We use Cloudflare as our content delivery network (CDN), GeoIP provider (IP Geo-location lookup) and Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) mitigation solution.  
The Cloudflare service privacy policy is available here: https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/

## Who we share your data with

We do not disclose your personal data to third parties. If any data processor would ever need to process our personal data, we will post those changes on this page.  
Upon registering for our website, you can explicitly opt-in to Receive (Promotional) Emails from the SamMobile Team. You can always opt-out of these Promotional emails at any time.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal data they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal data at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that data.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

For data removal (deletions), use our self-service removal page. In case of errors, contact: deletions@sammobile.freshdesk.com  
For data takeout (exports), use our self-service export page. In case of errors, contact: exports@sammobile.freshdesk.com

For all other contact details, you can use one of our preferred contact methods.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments are checked through an automated spam detection service (Akismet). The Akismet service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/

## Our contact information

SamMobile B.V.  
Blijenbergstraat 12N  
2406 GB  
Alphen aan den Rijn  
The Netherlands

## Additional information

If there are any questions or complaints regarding this Privacy & Cookies Policy you may contact us directly at privacy-questions-only@sammobile.com or through one of our preferred contact methods. **Please, only use this for questions or complaints and not to request data removal or data takeout, as these are specifically made self-service for easier and faster processing. Emailing instead will delay the process of handling your data removal or data takeout request and will make the process a lot harder and slower for those involved.**
